{"QandAList":
	[
		{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"What is WCF?","answer":"Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) is an SDK for developing and deploying services on Windows. WCF provides a runtime environment for services, enabling you to expose CLR types as services, and to consume other services as CLR types. WCF is part of .NET 3.0 and requires .NET 2.0, so it can only run on systems that support it."},
		{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"What is address in WCF and how many types of transport schemas are there in WCF?","answer":"Address is a way of letting client know that where a service is located. In WCF, every service is associated with a unique address. This contains the location of the service and transport schemas. WCF supports HTTP, TCP, Peer network, IPC (Inter-Process Communication over named pipes), MSMQ schemas."},
		{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"What is the difference WCF and Web services?","answer":"Web services can only be invoked by HTTP. While Service or a WCF component can be invoked by any protocol and any transport type. Second web services are not flexible. However, Services are flexible. If you make a new version of the service then you need to just expose a new end. Therefore, services are agile and which is a very practical approach looking at the current business trends."},
		{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"What are the main components of WCF?","answer":"1. Service class 2. Hosting environment 3. End point."},
		{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"Where we can host WCF services?","answer":"There are three ways of hosting WCF services. 1. IIS 2. Self Hosting 3. WAS - Windows Activation Service."},
		{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"What is endpoint in WCF?","answer":"Every service must have Address that defines where the service resides, Contract that defines what the service does and a Binding that defines how to communicate with the service. In WCF the relationship between Address, Contract and Binding is called Endpoint."},
		{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"What is binding and how many types of bindings are there in WCF?","answer":"A binding defines how an end point communicates to the world. A binding defines the transport (such as HTTP or TCP) and the encoding being used (such as text or binary). A binding can contain binding elements that specify details like the security mechanisms used to secure messages, or the message pattern used by an endpoint.  WCF supports nine types of bindings.( Basic binding, TCP binding, Peer network binding, IPC binding, Web Service (WS) binding, Federated WS binding, Duplex WS binding, MSMQ binding, MSMQ integration binding)."},
		{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"What are the various ways of hosting a WCF service?","answer":"There are three major ways to host a WCF service. 1. Self-hosting the service in one's own application domain.  The service comes in to existence when you create the object of ServiceHost class and the service closes when you call the Close of the Service Host class."},
		{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"What are the types of contract available in WCF?","answer":"a)Service Contract:Describes what operations the client can perform.b)Operation Contract : defines the method inside Interface of Service.c)Data Contract:Defines what data types are passed d)Message Contract:Defines whether a service can interact directly with messages"},
				{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"What is the proxy for WCF Service?","answer":"A proxy is a class by which a service client can Interact with the service.By the use of proxy in the client application we are able to call the different methods exposed by the service"},
				{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"How can we create Proxy for the WCF Service?","answer":"We can create proxy using the tool svcutil.exe after creating the service.We can use the following command at command line.svcutil.exe *.wsdl *.xsd /language:C# /out:SampleProxy.cs /config:app.config"},
				{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"What is the difference between WCF Service and Web Service?","answer":"a)WCF Service supports both http and tcp protocol while webservice supports only http protocol.b)WCF Service is more flexible than web service."},
				{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"What are SOAP Faults in WCF?","answer":"Common language runtime (CLR) exceptions do not flow across service boundaries. At the maximum, a CLR exceptions may propagate up to the service tier from business components. Unhandled CLR exceptions reach the service channel and are serialized as SOAP faults before reporting to clients. An unhandled CLR exception will fault the service channel, taking any existing sessions with it. That is why it is very important to convert the CLR exceptions into SOAP faults. Where possible, throw fault exceptions."},
				{"category":".NET","topic_id":"16","question":"What happens if there is an unhandled exception in WCF?","answer":"If there is an unhandled exception in WCF, the the service model returns a general SOAP fault, that does not include any exception specific details by default. However, you can include exception details in SOAP faults, using IncludeExceptionDetailsInFaults attribute. If IncludeExceptionDetailsInFaults is enabled, exception details including stack trace are included in the generated SOAP fault. IncludeExceptionDetailsInFaults should be enabled for debugging purposes only. Sending stack trace details is risky."}
	]
}